-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
讹诈专家
The Master  Blackmailer
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
根据原著"米尔沃顿案"改编
Based on 'Charles Augustus Milverton'
巴黎
Paris
我最亲爱的Emile
Emile my dearest one.
[法语]
[speaking french]
是的 夫人
Yes Madame.
我最亲爱的Emile
My dearest Emile,
我丈夫已经改变了计划
my husband has changed his plans.
没有其他的方式说再见
There is no other way to say goodbye.
把我记在你的心中
Remember me in your heart.
12年后
12 Years Later
谁在巴黎出卖了我
Who betrayed me in Paris
为什么你等这么久才来?
and why did you wait so long?
我发现你的贵妇风范令人吃惊
I find your ladyship's attitude surprising.
以上问题的答案与你无关
The answers to those questions are no concern of yours.
我乞求你
On my knees I beg you,
发发慈悲
I employ you to show mercy.
我可不管什么慈悲 夫人
I'm not in the business of mercy Madame.
我没有钱
I haven't the money.
即使我愿意给
Even if I wished
怎么能让我丈夫不发现呢?
how could I without my husband knowing?
连尝试都不去做...这种建议...
Oh you'd be exceedingly ill advised
是个馊主意
not to make an effort.
悉听尊便!
Do your worst.
你别想从我这里得到一个子
You will not have a penny from me,
胆小鬼!
coward!
我的孙子们已经受到了足够的惩罚
My grandsons were punished enough.
我很少收到他们的来信
I hear from them only seldom.
我想他们是不想让我伤心
They wish to spare me their misery I think.
这个魔鬼已经归西了吗?
This monster who brought about their downfall?
他还健在 福尔摩斯先生
He lives and breathes Mr. Holmes
面带笑容
with a smiling face
但内心冷酷无情
and a heart of marble.
你应该早点来找我
You should have come to me sooner.
如果能早点认识你
If only I'd known of you sooner.
我的一个朋友把你介绍给我
A friend gave me your name.
他对你的评价很高
He has a high regard,
就因为你的正义感
for your sense of justice.
你读诗吗?
Do you read poetry?
试试这页
Try a leaf.
C.A.M.魔鬼
CAM devil.
这是我能给你的唯一线索
This is the only clue I can offer you.
或许有用
Maybe it will help.
我不是为了自己 福尔摩斯先生
I wish nothing for myself Mr. Holmes.
那已经太晚了
It is too late for that.
我只希望...
I wish only
能拯救他人
to save others.
3:45去伦敦
3:45 for London.
在那里我觉得很悲哀
I felt great sadness there.
想到那个屋子
To think that that house
回荡着孩子们成长的声音
must have reverberated to the sounds of those boys growing up.
一个掠夺弱者的人
Man who preys upon weakness
面带微笑
with a smiling face
但冷酷无情
and a heart of marble.
一个讹诈专家
A master blackmailer.
我听过人们对他的私语
I've heard whisper of him
但是没人知道他的名字
yet no one has put a name to him.
从没人提及过讹诈之事
Well there's no mention of blackmail.
即使报纸的专栏也没有捕风捉影过
Even a whisper of a newspaper column.
你有记录吗?
You have reported it?
关于她的两个孙子
Of her two grandchildren,
大哥George
George the elder,
和Vike Kroft
and Vike Kroft
被人捉奸
was caught in a moment of indiscretion,
报纸上说是美人计
referred to the paper as the Badger Game.
好像是说这位绅士被妓女勾引上床
It seems to involve a gentleman being lured to the bed of a prostitute
然后被发现
then being discovered
捉奸在床
'In flagrante delicto' by a third party.
像往常一样 这些耸人听闻的报道又弄错了
As usual the sensational press has got it wrong.
那位女士确实是位演员
The lady was an actress that is true
但不是被逮个正着
but it was no [unintelligible]
Hudson太太!
Mrs. Hudson!
他结婚了 福尔摩斯
He was married Holmes
入赘的是全国最有影响力的家族
into one of the highest family's in the land.
报纸上大肆报道了一番
The paper's made plenty of that.
小一点的呢?
And the younger boy?
Edward
Edward.
他为他哥哥报仇
Now, he revenged for his brother,
用左轮枪打了男仆
took a revolver to the footman,
仆人叫...Veitch
who's name was, uh Veitch,
当面开的枪
burst in upon him,
子弹打到了脸上
shot him in the face.
这人还活着
The man lived
但已经毁容了
but was disfigured for life.
审判结束后 他就失踪了
After the trial he disappeared.
必须找到Veitch
It is Veitch we must find
他能带我们找到猎物
to lead us to our prize.
Hudson太太 你不舒服吗?
Ms. Hudson are you not well?
我很好
Of course I'm well.
你知道我讨厌卷心菜的味
Then please you know I hate the smell of cabbage.
兄弟俩肯定受了很多折磨
Surely the brothers would know they're tormenter.
哥哥很丢脸地离开了英国
The older brother fled the country in disgrace.
Edward服刑之后也去找他
Edward joined him having served his sentence,
他们现在在法国某个地方过着富裕的生活
they're now living richly somewhere in France.
再见 Hudson太太
Goodbye Mrs. Hudson.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有一个很奇怪
There is one curiosity.
C.A.M魔鬼
C.A.M Devil.
要是愿意 读读吧 找点线索
Read it for clues if you wish.
我更愿意读Henneson的诗
I rather liked Henneson.
以后再读
But later.
我希望你集中精力
I'd prefer you to direct your energies
看看闲话作家那段
towards the gossip columnists.
草原
The Grasslands.
草原 华生
The Grasslands Watson
毒蛇生活在那里
for which our serpent lies.
告诉我们你要去哪 Charlotte
Do tell us where you're going Charlotte.
说啊
Oh yes do tell.
Lottie你要去哪?
Lottie where are you going?
我可以吗  亲爱的
Shall I, dearest.
说什么?
What's that my love?
要告诉他们我们去哪度蜜月吗?
Tell them where we're going for our honeymoon.
我不反对
I've no objections.
是Buddley Solterton
It's Buddley Solterton.
太浪漫了
How romantic.
是很浪漫
It is actually very.
要是我就去国外什么地方度蜜月
I shall have to choose somewhere abroad for a honeymoon.
巴黎或是罗马
Paris or Rome.
也许吧 Daphne
You may Daphne.
但是要是命中注定要嫁给一个军人
But if one's fate is to marry a soldier,
那她一生就得漂泊异乡了
abroad may well be one's whole life.
你的蜜月呢  Eva小姐?
And your honeymoon Lady Eva?
你和Harry决定了吗?
Have you and Harry decided yet?
佛罗伦萨
Florence,
那不勒斯
Naples,
康斯汀坦布尔 我想吧
Constantinople I think.
听上去不错
Sounds delightful.
你让他嫉妒了
Now you've made him envious.
怎么会
Not at all.
Charlotte 亲爱的
Charlotte my dear,
我得回兵营了
I must return to barracks.
今晚能见到你吗?
Shall I see you this evening?
不行 职责所限
No, duties forbid.
团里有晚宴
Our regimental dinner alas.
女士们 再见
Ladies.
Lottie 他真不错
Lottie he is gorgeous.
也很可爱
He's divine.
你怎么有这福气找到Charlotte呢?
How'd you get so lucky Charlotte?
但是Buddley Solterton在哪?
But where is Buddley Solterton?
真为你高兴 Lottie
Oh I'm so happy for you Lottie.
这是什么?
What is this?
不是出自我的手
It's not in my hand.
亲爱的上校
My dear Colonel
你不会想我把原件给你看吧?
you don't expect me to give you the original do you?
你从哪得到的?
Where did you get this?
谁给你的?
Who gave it to you?
嗯
Oh well,
除了你心爱之人还有谁?
who but the object of your affections.
我不信
I don't believe it.
不可能
It's not possible.
你想从我这儿得到什么?
What do you want from me?
-1200磅! -什么?!
Two hundred pounds! What?
这么点就能搞定一切
For it all to be blown away.
做梦! 一分钱我都不给!
Never! I won't part with a penny.
我要先看着你下地狱
I'll see you in hell first.
想想你可爱的新娘 上校
Think of your lovely bride Colonel.
你对我做了什么?
What have you done to me?
每个人都要问问自己
One has to ask oneself
能吃多少黄油?
how much butter can one eat?
Dotty Martian很明显
Dotty Martian apparently
能吃17勺盐外加一些胡椒粉
got seventeen salt and pepper parts.
17勺?
Seventeen?
是真的
It's true.
我想到了一个解决的办法
I was thinking of a way of dealing with it
-就是... -帮我一下
was to... Help me.
给她写封礼貌的信
Was to mail her politely,
一直都挺有用 直到再也没用
always useful until the awful day when always useless,
她就告诉了公爵夫人
she said to the Duchess.
-不是吧 -是真的
-No. -Yes, it's true.
Lillie无意中听到的 是吧Lillie?
Lillie overheard her didn't you Lillie?
是的 小姐
Yes my lady.
Harry想在海上举行婚礼
Harry wanted us to be married at sea
在一艘私人游船上 只有船员参加
on a pirate ship with only the crew invited
但是谁也不能这样 是吧?
but one really can't can we?
是啊 没人真能那样
No my dear one really can't.
我下了一个极愚蠢的赌注
I made an extremely foolish wager
结果最后我和一个重骑兵干上了
but I ended up boxing a dragoon.
这三天里 这场婚礼还有什么要完善的吗?
And will you mend for the nuptials, my dear fellow, in three days?
你还是有点小小的焦虑吧
You have a small flutter in itself.
给凉脚丫的厚袜子
Thick socks for cold feet.
要希望它们派不上用场都很难
You can rarely hopes they won't be needed.
是的 我祖父幻想自己是个拳击手
Yeah my grandfather fancied himself as something of a pugilist.
他是个魁梧的人
He was a fortho.
我记得有一年夏天在爱尔兰
I remember one summer in Ireland,
我那时大概有8岁了
I must have been about eight years old I suppose.
他决定给我上一课
He decided to give me a lesson,
我从没有那么害怕过
I've never been so frightened in my life.
Lottie 这是什么?
Lottie what is it?
Lottie?
出什么事了?
What's the problem?
是信...
There's some letters.
什么?
What?
看来去不成Buddley Solterton了
Looks like it's goodbye Buddley Solterton.
我必须去看看她
I must go to her.
别去 亲爱的
No my angel.
Muir王子要迎娶Haganlod男爵之女
Prince Muir is about to marry Baroness Haganlod.
他第一任妻子Mary Devagram公主 在10年前去世
Lost his first wife, Princess Mary Devagram ten years ago.
Rosebury阁下受邀
Lord Rosebury has accepted an invitation
将参加在Sheffield举行的Cutler家宴
to dine at the Cutler's Feast in Sheffield.
你心不在焉 华生
You're not trying Watson.
是吗 福尔摩斯?
Well really Holmes?
我一直在读报纸
I've been reading things out
自从今早8点开始
since half past eight this morning.
没有一篇文章让你有反应
You haven't reacted to a single article.
我会的 我保证
I shall react I assure you
只要你有东西吸引到我
the moment you read out something which catches my attention.
这个有意思
Oh this is interesting.
Lord Hockstein英格兰板球队
Lord Hockstein of English Cricketers
下个月要去费城和多伦多
are leaving next monthfor Philadelphia and Toronto.
那些地方的人究竟对板球了解多少?
What on earth does that continent know about cricket?
尊贵的Miles小姐
The honorable Miss Miles
在婚礼的两天前 解除了与Dorking上校的婚约
has broken off her engagement to Colonel Dorking two days before the wedding.
今年冬天女性最重要的一样打扮
The most important item in a woman's appearance this winter
是她的帽子头饰
will be her headgear.
进来
Yes?
先生 我来给您生火
I've come to light the fire for you sir.
不是现在 谢谢
Not at the moment thank you.
走开
Go away.
警督?
Inspector?
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
嗯 是
Yes.
这是Dorking上校的来信
It's from Colonel Dorking.
谁送来的?
Who delivered it?
他的勤务兵
His batman.
上面是Dorking上校
This is Colonel Dorking.
他和Miles小姐的婚礼
His engagement to the honorable Miss Miles
在昨天取消了
was broken off yesterday.
你瞧 我有听
You see I was listening.
是Lastrade
It's Lastrade.
我不知道他是否在楼上 警督
I don't know that he's in Inspector.
警督?
Inspector?
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
你知道我为什么来
you know what I'm here for.
不知道 和我说说
No prey tell me.
为了那封信
I've come for the letter,
就在那个信封里
which arrived in that envelope.
那是被偷出来的
It was stolen from the rooms
在John Dorking上校的房间里
of Colonel John Dorking
然后到了华生医生手里
and delivered into the hands of Doctor Watson
在不到20分钟的时间里
not twenty minutes ago.
现在在你手上吗?
Do you have it?
是有送来 但算是"偷"吗?
Delivered, yes but stolen?
这是给我的私人信件 Lastrade
It was a postal note to me Lastrade.
这是警方的证据
It's police evidence.
上校已经死了
The Colonel is dead.
是的 我们知道
Yes we know.
自杀
by his own hand.
并没有什么凶杀的嫌疑 不是吗?
Foul play is not suspected is it?
你怎么这么肯定?
How can you be so sure it isn't?
信上说得很明白
Because the note made it clear.
那么...
So,
要是他想自杀
why should he write to you
为什么还要给你写信?
if he's topping himself?
你认识他吗?
Did you know the man?
我不认识他
I had no knowledge of him.
那回答我的问题
Oh answer my question
或者 还是把信给我
or better still show me the letter.
它不会告诉你什么
It will tell you nothing.
那么在我看来
So it seems to me
既然雇了你
on the point of engaging you
他一定是改变了主意
he must have changed his mind.
并用士兵的方式了结了一切
And took a soldier's way out.
他那么说是什么意思...
What does he mean by
这我们永远不会知道了 警督
We'll never know Inspector.
但是他已经订婚了呀 该死的
But he was engaged to be married damn it.
是的
Yes.
这种事不会是第一次
Well wouldn't be the first time
也不会是最后一件
and it won't be the last.
这么说这是敲诈?
So it was blackmail you'd say?
说得好 Lastrade
Well done Lastrade.
别挖苦我了 福尔摩斯先生
No need for sarcasm Mr. Holmes.
你跟我们差不多
Your as much in the dark,
也是毫无头绪吧
as we are then
也不知道这个敲诈者是谁
about who this blackmailer might be.
有一件事你可以肯定
You can be sure of one thing
Colonel Dorking不是他的第一个受害人
Colonel Dorking was not his first victim
也不会是最后一个
and will not be his last.
再见 Lastrade
Goodbye Lastrade.
如果你有什么消息
You will let me know
你会通知我的吧?
if you hear of anything?
我犯下了一个弥天大错
I made a hideous mistake.
我需要你的出马
I need your services.
唯一可惜的是 他没有说出敲诈者的名字
The only pity is he didn't name the blackmailer.
他有
He did.
这是和信在一起的
This came with the letter.
Charles Augustus Milverton
Charles Augustus Milverton,
Hampstead区Appledore Towers...画商
Appledore Towers, Hampstead, Art Dealer.
他的伪装
Camouflage.
C-A-M
C-A-M,
C.A.M.
在我的办案生涯里 我和50个凶手打过交道
I've had to deal with fifty murderers in my career,
但就算是其中最凶残一个
but the worst of them never gave me
也没有这位Charles Augustus Milverton先生
this sense of revulsion which that I feel at this moment towards
这么让我厌恶
Mr. Charles Augustus Milverton.
Milverton的老窝
Milverton's lair.
这是座堡垒
It's a fortress.
出乎你的意料吗?
Are you surprised?
Charles Augustus
他是个外国人吗?
Is he a foreigner,
罗马人?
Roman?
他给自己建了座监狱
He's built his own prison.
他是个反人类的人
He's a man who loathes the human race.
什么样的成长环境会让他变成现在这样?
What circumstances might bring him to that?
孩提时代孤独地被养大
Well boy brought up in lonely isolation,
缺少关爱
starved of affection.
很可能是生活在伦敦的郊区
Probably in one of London's outer suburbs.
郊区? 为什么不是Soho区 或是Lesters Square那里?
Outer, why not Soho or Lesters Square.
因为...我亲爱的福尔摩斯... 那些个地方
Cause, my dear Holmes, those places
就算恶人们像狼群一样出没
with all there vices team like wolves,
还是有好的风气和人性的
generosity of spirit and humanity.
有意思
That's interesting.
Milverton
Milverton.
今晚我要派给你一个任务
Tonight I have an assignment for you
愿意去走访一间画廊吗?
if you're willing to visit an art gallery.
那你干什么呢?
What will you be doing?
你难道不觉得那个尊贵的Miles小姐
Don't you think that the honorable Miss Miles
更值得一访吗?
might be more worth a visit
既然Dorking写信给了你?
since Dorking wrote to you?
那是过去了 华生
That is past Watson.
我们现在要做的
What we must do now
是紧紧盯上他的下一个受害者
is fastened ourselves onto his next victim.
所以这个晚上我要尽可能地去了解Milverton?
So this evening I'm to discover all I can about Milverton?
他的名声 他的背景
His reputation. His background.
以及对他的感受
And how those perceive him.
我要和他谈话吗?
Do I engage him in conversation?
是的 但是小心些
Yes but with caution.
先生在吃午饭的时候病倒了 小姐
His lordship has taken ill at lunch my lady.
恐怕是次中风
It is feared he may have suffered a stroke.
可怜的Charles叔叔
Oh poor Uncle Charles.
夫人正在陪他
Her ladyship is with him now.
知道你回来了他会很高兴
He should be pleased that you're back.
Diana
Oh Diana.
我能见见他吗?
May I see him?
他睡着了
He's sleeping.
等一会儿吧
Wait a little.
有多糟糕?
How bad is it?
Bainey医生不太乐观
Doctor Bainey's not optimistic.
如果他活了下来
If he lives
也会是瘫痪
he'll be paralyzed.
Eva 今天晚上 我有个仪式需要参加
Eva there's a ceremony that I have to attend this evening.
为一位年轻艺术家为我画的肖像揭幕
The unveiling of my portrait by a young artist.
只需去露个面
Just a brief appearance
但是我答应他会到场
but I promised him that I'd be there.
你愿意照顾他吗?
Will you come take care of him?
当然愿意
Of course.
等等
Wait.
进来
Yes?
来了一个侍女
Here's a maid.
是为了活来的 先生
Come about the job sir.
那就进来吧
Well come in then.
你有什么可以卖给我的 亲爱的?
So what have you got to sell me my dear?
你叫什么名字?
What is your name?
Lillie 先生
Lillie sir.
啊 Eva Blackwell女士
Awe, Lady Eva Blackwell.
我突然想到
It occurs to me
我没有被邀请
that I mightnot have been
就去看展览 福尔摩斯
invited to this viewing Holmes.
如果不让我进怎么办?
What if I'm not admitted huh?
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
福尔摩斯先生刚出去了吗?
Is that Mr. Holmes just going out?
我也没有看清楚 医生
Not that I recognize Doctor.
女士们先生们 闲话不说
Without more ado ladies and gentlemen
为了它我们聚集在此
I shall perform the ceremony
由我来主持这场仪式
for which we are gathered.
我觉得本人更温柔 更美丽
I think she's gentler and more beautiful than that.
我应该坚持让Whistler为你作画
I should insist on Whistler painting you.
荣幸之至
It was a great honor.
我会很快离开
I would like to go soon.
男孩画笔下的你至臻至美 Swinstead女士
The boy has caught you to perfection Lady Swinstead.
我们没有被引荐过吧
I don't believe we've been introduced.
Charles Augustus Milverton
为您效劳
at your service.
借光
Excuse me,
Swinstead女士 恕我冒昧
Lady Swinstead, I'm afraid.
我的丈夫?
My husband?
Eva
Eva.
请原谅
Forgive me.
非常漂亮的一位女士
A most beautiful lady.
什么?
What?
Swinstead女士
Lady Swinstead.
不过我在想...
I wonder though
他是不是画对了她的嘴唇
if he's quite got her mouth right.
失败啊
Disaster.
我认识你吗?
Do I know you?
嗯
Yeah.
你为Milverton工作 不是吗?
You work for Milverton don't you?
为他干活好吗?
Is he good to work for?
要是没有那可恶的水管就还不错
He would be if weren't for the bloody plumbing.
水管?
Plumbing?
永远都漏水
Always drippin off the spout
永远都是我的错
and it's always my fault.
看看你干了什么
Look what you've done.
-这杯是我的 对吗? -是的
That's my pint is it?
我们来亲个嘴儿
Now give us a kiss.
滚开
Get off.
滚开 Robert
Get off Robert.
滚开
Get off.
我们从没叫过水管工
We never sent for the plumber.
你好
Oh hello.
是Stokes叫我来的
It was Stokes.
是吗?
Oh was it?
Robert 这是... 你叫什么?
Robert this is...what's your name?
Escott
Escott.
"我们一管到底"
We plumb the depths,
我公司的座右铭
it's my firms motto.
他说是你叫来的
He says you sent for him.
那麻烦在哪儿?
Where's the trouble?
啊 我看到了
Awe, I see.
这里怎么回事?
What's going on here?
我在问你这里发生了什么事情?
I asked you what's going on here?
他是来修水管的 Hebworth先生
He's come about the plumbing Mr. Hebworth.
我自作主张叫他来看看
I took the liberty of asking him to come and look at it.
不是吗 Aggie?
Didn't I Aggie?
你没有自作主张的权利
You have no right to take liberties.
这里归我管
I'm in charge here.
但是我们得修好它 Hebworth先生
But we do need it done Mr. Hebworth.
我是说 Milverton先生昨天还在说
I mean, Mr. Milverton was only saying yesterday
管子里传出一股很难闻的味道
that there was a very, ugly smell coming from the piping.
好吧
Very well.
那就继续吧
Carry on then.
他早出晚归
He came in late and went out early.
谢谢你 Hudson太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson.
真遗憾啊
Shame isn't it?
他是个优秀的政治家 华生
He was a fine statesmen Watson.
听说 他的交际手腕
It was his diplomacy, I'm told,
在几年前那段非常时期里
which eased Anglo-French relationships
缓和了美国和法国之间的紧张关系
at a most delicate time some year's back.
他的遗孀听到这心碎的消息时 我也在场呢
To think that I was there with his widow when the news was broken to her.
Milverton
Milverton.
我和他聊了几句
I exchanged a word with him.
一副充满算计 虚情假意的笑容
A more calculatingly insincere smile
我真希望再也不要看到
I never hope to see.
Charles Augustus
Charles Augustus.
据说他是一名艺术领域的鉴赏家
And described to me as a connoisseur in art matters.
一个商人 只要他出马
A businessman who can make or raise
就能让任何一名艺术家发家致富
the fortune's of any artist to whom he devotes himself.
不知廉耻
Stems of hell!
他是许多伦敦俱乐部里的会员
He's a member of a number of London clubs.
因此我猜测
On the basis I suppose
那些人并不和他唱反调
that there are those who do not oppose him.
但Diogenes俱乐部不是 (福尔摩斯哥哥的俱乐部 见"希腊议员案")
Not the Diogenes.
我听我的哥哥Microft说
I heard my brother Microft
他自己找上门来 结果碰了一鼻子灰走了
that he presented himself and was turned away with a flea in his ear.
你的这位绅士敲诈犯
You're gentleman blackmailer
出生在Balum
was born in Balum.
一个磨工和他妻子的独子
The only son of a glazer and his wife.
你从哪儿听说的?
Your source of information?
很多地方
Oh a variety of sources.
我用了你的方法
I applied your methods.
你乔装成了谁?
How have you faired?
我进入了堡垒
I've entered the fortress
我是个生意兴隆的水管工
I'm a plumber of a rising business,
化名Escotts
Escotts my name.
男管家名叫Hebworth
The butler, who goes under the name of Hebworth,
不是别人 正是那个男仆Veitch
is none other than Veitch the footman,
脸上中了枪 我敢肯定
who was shot in the face. I'm certain of it.
或许Milverton之所以雇了他
Perhaps he was employed by Milverton
是作为他在Kroft丑闻事件中
as a reward for keeping his silence
保持沉默的奖励
during the Kroft scandal.
我很想知道
I wonder.
你的管道被空气堵塞了  Hebworth先生
You got air compression in your cell pipes Mr. Hebworth.
才让这房子里一股臭味
That's the cause of the evil smell in this house.
这些在下面接水
What this warrants is a save all below it
脏水就不会淤积了
so the dirty water don't get clogged up.
你在这里干什么!
What the devil are you doing here?
他是个水管工 先生
It's the plumber sir.
这屋子里不需要水管工
There's no need of a plumber in this room.
滚出去
Get out.
这是主人的特别房间
This is masters special room.
你现在就出去! 你这蠢货!
and you stay out now.
Aggie?
待会儿见 是我的水管工来了
I'll see you later it's my plumber.
Aggie?
我不在乎是不是让他吃醋了
I don't care if I do make him jealous.
他的主意....
His ideas are...
我不喜欢你的主人 Aggie
I don't like your master Aggie.
我觉得他不像个好人
I think he's a shady character.
你说得没错
Your right he is.
我的天
Oh God.
Lillie
Lillie.
她不会为了那活过来做的
She won't come here for that Job.
她干嘛想到这里来做呢?
Why would she want to work here for?
她才是个真正的侍女
She was a real lady's maid,
从她的穿着你就能看出来
you could tell by her clothes.
那她是为了什么来呢?
What was she after then?
我觉得你有点太好奇了
I think you're getting to a bit too curious.
是的 没错
Yes you are
我觉得好冷
and I'm getting cold.
好舒服
Snuggling good.
就亲一下
Just a kiss.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how.
小可怜
Poor boy.
福尔摩斯
Holmes
我有了个主意
I've had an idea.
一个我们可以把Milverton
A way in which we bring this fellow Milverton
绳之以法的办法
within the grasp of the law.
如果我们能引诱他去敲诈
If we could tempt him to blackmail
一个无辜的人 我们就能抓住他了
an innocent person we should have him.
现在假设...
Now suppose...
我收到了一些不体面的信
suppose I was to be the recipient of some indiscreet letters.
你吗 华生?
You Watson?
那谁写这些信呢?
Who would prey write these letters?
某个我们的熟人
Someone of our acquaintance.
而你身为一个水管工
And you and your plumbing persona
可以把它们拿去卖
could offer them for sale.
而在交易的过程中
And at the moment of transaction
Lastrade就可以随时逮捕他
Lastrade would be on hand to arrest him.
但是法律上说 我们无法行动
But legally we cannot move
直到某个被害人准备好了
until some victim is prepared
牺牲自己的名声
to sacrifice their reputation
跑去警察局
by going to the police.
一定有什么办法
There must be some way
可以让我们打倒这个恶魔
we can fight this devil.
有的
There is.
在过不到三个星期 亲爱的
In a mere three weeks, my love,
这将都是你的
this all will be yours.
-我觉得配不上 -胡说
-I feel unworthy of it. -Nonsense.
那世上就没有女人能配得上了
There's no woman on earth more worthy.
我觉得不舒服
I feel unwell.
我知道你在牵挂什么
I know what it is your feeling.
是你的叔叔Charles 我理解
It's your Uncle Charles, I do understand.
我们会先安排后事
We have our future ahead.
然后我们共度余生
We have each other for the rest of our lives.
我能在哪里找到Vetron先生?
Where can I find Monsieur Vetron?
夏洛克 福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
晚上好 先生
Good evening monsieur.
你瞧我正努力
You see I've tried to bring
想把一点巴黎的风情带到伦敦
a little bit of Paris to London.
Camile的手法很简单 (Camile:一种竹节条格花纹)
Camille [unintelligible] is simple.
Camile?
Camille?
C-A-M...C.A.M.
C-A-M, C.A.M.
华生 你知道吗 有时候你真让我惊叹
Watson you know sometimes you absolutely amaze me.
他希望被人知道
He allows it to be known
他准备好了出一大笔钱
that he is prepared to pay very high sums
买那些尊贵富有 地位显赫的人的信
for letters, which come from wise people of wealth and position.
你收到过...收到过来自男仆或者侍女的信吗?
Do you receive, do you receive these letters from valets and maids?
不只他们
Not only them
有时候...怎么说...
sometimes, how do you say,
还从异教徒的恶棍手里得到
gentile ruffian
他们从爱上他们 容易轻信的女人 那里得到那些秘密
who have the confidence and affection of trusting women?
谁也不知道Camille的魔爪会伸向谁
No one knows where Camille's grip may fall.
你是他的代理 他的执事?
You are his agent, his conductor?
我?
Me?
不 不 我们只是很早之前有过交情
No, no, no, we go back a number of years.
很少有人会这么蠢
Rarely people are stupid enough
去相信他们的下人
to trust their servants.
你最近是不是给他介绍了一个女仆?
Did you help conduct a housemaid to him recently?
你为什么会有兴趣呢 先生?
And what his your interest monsieur?
我有个朋友 或许有些东西想要脱手
I have a friend who may have something to sell.
哦是吗?
Oh yes?
这边请
Well come this way.
跟我说说他
Tell me about him.
他需要知道流程
Well he needs to know the procedure.
这事很棘手
The matter is delicate.
那是当然
Of course.
向来如此
It always is.
他是个私人医生
He's a personal physician
为Landish公爵和公爵夫人效力
to the Duke and Duchess of Landish.
新来的这个女仆呢?
Now this housemaid who came by recently?
今晚她在这里
She's here tonight
庆祝自己的生日
celebrating her birthday.
从现在起一年里
In a year from now
她会是个自由人
she'll be on the streets.
代价呢?
At whose expense?
Eva Blackwell女士
Lady Eva Blackwell.
与Dovercourt伯爵订婚
Engaged to the Earl of Dovercourt.
据说几个星期里就会结婚了
Said to be married within weeks.
她必须受到我们的保护
She must submit herself to our care.
事不宜迟
Somehow without delay.
你怎么敢进来
How dare you come into this house.
你怎么敢?
How dare you.
我亲爱的女士
My dear young lady
发脾气可没有用
a show of temper will avail you nothing.
我付不了钱
I can't pay you.
我没有钱付给你
I haven't the money to pay you.
把我的信还给我
Give me back my letters.
求你
Please
放过我吧
Ieave me alone.
你一定有不少地方 可以找到钱
You must be resourceful in finding the money.
你有有权有势的朋友
You have influential friends.
他们肯定会来帮你
Surely they'll come to your aid.
不 他们不会
No they won't.
我能对谁开口呢?
Who can I tell?
这我不在乎
That's not my concern.
小姐 是Dovercourt伯爵
The Earl of Dovercourt my lady.
别紧张 来的是个好人
Don't fuss. Oh there's a good fellow.
Henry
Now Henry.
这位是Milverton先生
This is Mr. Milverton.
很荣幸能结识您 阁下
I'm honored to meet you my Lord.
你在这里干什么?
And what is your business here?
干什么?
Business?
我们要与这位爵爷
Shall we share with his lordship
分享一下我们的小秘密吗 Eva小姐?
our little secret Lady Eva?
不
No.
那就如你所愿
As you wish.
我的名片 先生
My card sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
再见了 两位
Good day at you both.
Stokes?
几点了?
What time is it?
四点过二十
Twenty past four.
还要多久 Escott?
How much longer Escott?
请您原谅我要说的话 Hebworth先生
Well if you'll forgive me for saying so Mr. Hebworth,
你们的管子已经坏得很严重了
you're plumbing's in the shocking stage.
我从没见过这么糟糕的情况
It's the worst I've ever seen.
再给你两天
Two more days
你就滚蛋
then you're out.
今晚来见我
Come and see me tonight.
Aggie
Oh Aggie.
我得到可靠消息
I have it under authority
她每个星期日下午从这里骑马经过
that she rides this way every Sunday afternoon.
你能认出她吗?
Would you recognize her?
我在杂志上见过她
Well I've seen her likeness in a magazine
如果她是和Dovercourt在一起 或许能吧
if she's with Dovercourt, I might.
Eva?
马童 勒住马
Boy get the horse.
我是个医生
I'm a Doctor.
她的教母正好住在那边
Her godmother lives just over there.
如果移动是安全的话 我们可以带她过去 医生
We could carry her if it's safe to lift her doctor.
是的 没有受伤 只是晕倒而已
Yes. There's no injury
亲爱的
Darling?
真对不起引来那么大的麻烦
I'm so sorry to be of so much trouble.
你躺在原地别动 亲爱的
You lay where you are my dear.
你现在很安全
You're in safe hands now.
Swinstead女士
Lady Swinstead.
整个英格兰都与您同哀
All England shares in your grief.
我的同事 华生医生 正在为Eva小姐治疗
My colleague, Doctor Watson, is attending Lady Eva.
可怜的孩子 因为我丈夫的死心乱如麻
Poor child is very disturbed by the death of my husband.
没有什么大碍 Swinstead女士
There's nothing serious Lady Swinstead
但是我建议你让她休息一阵
but I would advise you to make her rest
让她自己的医生看看她
and get her own doctor to see her.
当然会的
Of course.
谢谢你 华生医生
Thank you Doctor Watson.
或许Eva小姐需要我为她效劳
May Lady Eva need my services
请收下
please.
Eva?
是Milverton让她摔下马的
It was Milverton who caused her fall.
她看见了他的马车
She saw his carriage.
他让他的受害人精神紧张
He rings the nerves of his victims
让自己原本就鼓鼓的钱包更鼓
to add to his already swollen moneybags.
他是伦敦最差劲的男人
He is the worst man in London.
偷鸡摸狗 诡计多端
Seething, slithering and sly.
难道除了留在这里
Yes is there nothing better we can do
我们没有别的可做了吗 福尔摩斯?
than spend our time here Holmes?
你有什么建议吗?
You have any suggestions?
和他对质 讨个说法
Confront him. Challenge him.
先动脑子再动手
The brain before the cudgel rule.
同时
Meanwhile,
他会故伎重演
just like him,
不断勒索他的受害人
he'll squeeze his victims
直到把他们榨干为止
till he's drained them dry
我们却不去阻止他
and we're doing nothing to stop him.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
你必须吃饭 孩子
You must eat child.
什么让你烦恼?
What's troubling you?
你在等谁来吗?
Are you expecting someone?
没有
No.
我只是在想我的婚事
I'm just thinking about my wedding.
现在告诉我实话
Now tell me the truth.
抓住你了!
Gotchya?
这房子里的人几点上床 Aggie?
What time do they go to bed in this house Aggie?
你想知道这个干什么?
What do you want to know for?
我就可以知道什么时候来看你是安全的
So I know when it's safe to visit you.
你可以随时到墙边来
You could always come in over the wall.
用小卵石敲我的窗户
Throw pebbles at my window.
哪扇是你的窗?
Which is your window?
如果你娶了我
I'll only tell you
我就告诉你 亲爱的
if you marry me love.
-Aggie 我不能 -那我就不告诉你
-Oh Aggie I can't. -Then I wont tell.
你总是那么牙尖嘴利
You have such a way with words.
好吧
All right.
我在最上面的角落里
I'm at the very, very top on the corner
而主人 他在下面一层
and Master, he's a floor below
但是他靠近花园
but he's next to the garden
Hebworth先生
and Monsieur Hebworth
他在一楼
he's on the ground floor
穿过书房就是
just across from the study.
Lewis睡觉的时候 你来了也吵不醒他
Lewis is sleeping don't you come wake him.
仆人厅里一直流传这个笑话
There's a joke in the servant's hall.
为什么他不睡楼上呢?
Why don't he sleep upstairs?
因为主人想让他看门
Because the master wants him on guard.
他怕夜贼
He's afraid of burglars.
你是夜贼吗?
Are you a burglar?
我被你打动了
You touched my heart.
我会把你当成是我的礼物
I will make you a gift of mine.
出来
Off you go.
Maximilian 谁让你出来的?
Maximilian, who let you out.
停下
Stop.
过来
Come here.
Robert 停下
Robert, Stop it.
停下
Stop it.
我会抓住你的 Escott
I'll get you Escott.
他就在那拐角处
He's just around the corner.
为什么这么大吵大闹?
What's this bloody racket?
是...
Well there...
华生 你会很有兴趣听到下面这个消息
Watson you'll be interested to hear
我订婚了
that I'm engaged to be married.
是吗?
Oh yeah?
和Milverton的女仆
To the Milverton's housemaid.
我的天
Good heavens.
我需要线索
I needed information.
可你做得太过火了
Surely you've gone too far.
这是必不得已
It was a most necessary step.
我和她一起散步
I've walked with her,
和她聊天
talked with her.
天晓得谈了什么
heaven knows talks.
但是这女孩怎么办
But the girl?
没有办法 华生
Can't help it Watson.
在这种赌博下
One must play one's cards as best one can
必须出好每一手牌
when such a stake is on the table.
不过 我很高兴告诉你
However, I rejoice to tell you
我有个讨厌的竞争对手
that I have a hated rival
在我离开的时候
that will cut me out
就会挤掉我的位置
the moment my back is turned.
真是妙不可言的一天
What a splendid day it is.
你喜欢这天气?
You like this weather?
她来了
She's here.
我父亲在我十二岁的时候过世了
My father died when I was 12.
我母亲留在这个国家里
My mother stays in the country.
Swinstead阁下和夫人
Lord and Lady Swinstead
让我在伦敦有家的感觉
have made London home to me
去年安排我参加了社交季
but indeed they arranged my season last year.
给我你的手套
Give me your gloves.
Hudson太太
Oh Mrs. Hudson,
你这是在干什么?
what do you think you're doing?
整个早上你都没有出门 福尔摩斯先生
You haven't been out this morning Mr. Holmes
不做一个侦探 也能看这位年轻女士
and you don't have to be a detective to see that this young lady
大病初愈
is recently up from a sick bed.
不是吗 亲爱的?
Isn't that so my dear?
我们必须让她的脸颊重现红润
We must put some roses back in those cheeks.
谢谢
Thank you.
一碗热汤真是个好主意
The broth is an excellent idea.
Hudson太太 请离开一下好吗?
Mrs. Hudson will you vanish?
我说了离开
I said vanish.
他是我的初恋
He was my first love.
在Suffick我们邻居家的儿子
The son of some neighbors of ours in Suffick
但是我们门不当户不对
but we were ill matched.
他没有什么前途
He had few prospects.
当我来到伦敦
When I came down to London
参加去年的社交季
Iast year for the season
我便和他分手了
I broke off with him.
我没有意识到自己让他有多伤心
I didn't realize how much I hurt him.
他退回了我的信
He returned my letters
我把它们放进了箱子
and I put them away in a trunk,
一直保管着
which I keep with me.
那些信写了什么?
Now the substance of these letters?
一些蠢话
They're just a little foolish.
却足够引起你未婚夫的怀疑?
But sufficient to cause your fiance misgiving?
Harry如此为我骄傲
Harry's so proud of me.
有时我真害怕
It frightens me sometimes
如果自己辜负了他的期望
that I cannot live up to his expectation of me.
是你的侍女发现的信吗?
Was it your maid who found these letters?
是Lillie 是的
Lillie yes.
我相信过她
I trusted her.
我不敢相信
I cannot believe
她会这样背叛我
she could have betrayed me like this.
这个 Lillie怎么会知道Milverton?
How would this Lillie know about Milverton?
我想她之所以会想到这个主意
I think the idea may have come to her
是因为之前发生在我朋友身上的不幸
through a misfortune that befell a friend of mine,
Charlotte 她原本要结婚
Charlotte, who was to have married
嫁给Dorking上校
a Colonel Dorking.
Milverton先生给她寄去了些信
And Mr. Milverton sent her some letters.
都是些让人痛苦的信
They were very distressing.
当她收到信时 Lillie和我都在场
Lillie and I were there when she received them.
没想到同样的命运会降临到我身上
To think the same fate has befallen me.
一切都会过去的 Eva小姐
It will be all right Lady Eva.
你能做什么呢?
What could you do?
我的婚礼在18日
My marriage is on the 18th.
他提出要求
He's demanding that
要在婚礼前四天
the money be paid to him
也就是14日付钱给他
four days prior to the wedding on the 14th,
在舞会那天
on the day of the dance.
舞会?
Dance?
Dovercourt阁下安排了一次婚宴
Lord Dovercourt has arranged a wedding feast
邀请了伦敦一半的人
and invited half of London.
我担心死了
I'm dreading it.
如果你愿意让我全权代理
If you will place yourself in my hands
我会通知Milverton先生
I'll inform Mr. Milverton
你授权让我和他见面
that you've commissioned me to meet him
让我尽量谈到最好的条件?
to make the best terms that I can huh?
我积蓄有限 福尔摩斯先生
I have limited resources Mr. Holmes.
但足够我去和他讨价还价了
But enough for me to bargain with
我不能空着手去
I cannot approach him empty handed.
可以了
Good.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为我向您的教母问好
My best wishes to your Godmother.
Eva小姐
Lady Eva?
你必须相信福尔摩斯先生
You must trust Mr. Holmes
和他的方法
and his methods.
完全地信任
Absolutely.
Hudson太太会送你出门
Mrs. Hudson will see you out.
那位年轻女士 福尔摩斯
That young lady, Holmes,
显然得到了极大的关照
must be treated with infinite care
一点都不像你最近其它的恶作剧
unlike your other recent escapade.
华生
Oh Watson,
她能独自前来已经是鼓足了勇气
it took some nerve for her to come here alone.
我相信Eva小姐
It is my belief that Lady Eva
和Milverton的侍女
and the Milverton housemaid
有某个共同点
have something in common.
是什么呢?
And what is that?
活力
Juice.
华生 活力
Watson juice
在面对逆境的时候
in the face of adversity.
现在 Milverton先生
Now Mr. Milverton.
唉呦 唉呦 唉呦
Well, well, well.
Eva?
Lottie
Lottie.
真高兴见到你
I am so glad to see you.
巴黎不是答案
Paris wasn't the answer.
找到你真不容易
You've been hard to find.
你在干什么?
What were you doing?
我睡着了
I fell asleep.
Johnson告诉了我你叔叔Charles的事
Johnson told me about your Uncle Charles.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我留在这里是为了安慰Diana 但是...
I stayed here to comfort Diana but
这房子太悲伤了
this house is so sad.
我们6点半再登门
We'll call again at 6:30.
C.A.M
C-A-M.
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
是的
Yes.
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
这位先生...这样谨慎吗?
This gentlemen is it discreet?
华生是我的朋友和搭档
Dr. Watson is my friend and partner.
纯粹出于对你委托人利益的考虑
It is purely in the interest of your client
我表示反对
that I protest it.
这件事很棘手
The matter is so very delicate.
华生医生已经想到这点了
Dr. Watson has already thought of that.
请允许我?
May I?
谢谢
Oh thank you.
那我们就来谈买卖吧
Then we may proceed to business.
你在你的留言里说
You said in your note
你是Eva女士的全权代表
that you are acting for the Lady Eva,
那你有权接受我的条件吗?
are you empowered to accept my terms?
你的条件是什么?
What are your terms?
7000磅?
Seven thousand pounds?
另一种选择呢?
And the alternative?
亲爱的先生
My dear sir,
讨论这个我很不好受
it is painful for me to discuss it
但是我可以说
but I can say
这是出于极为慎重的考量
that all of this is done with most careful consideration
如果在14日那天没有付钱
and if the money is not paid on the 14th then there certainly
那么18日那天也不会有什么婚礼
will be no marriage on the 1 8th.
我们当然熟悉那些信的内容
We are, of course, familiar with the contents of these letters.
我们会建议我们的委托人
We shall advise our client
把整个故事告诉她未来的丈夫
to tell her future husband the whole story
相信他的宽宏大量
and trust to his generosity.
那你显然是不了解伯爵的为人
Well then you evidently do not know the Earl.
那些信里到底有什么能伤人的地方
What harm is there in these letters?
遣词很活泼
They are sprightly
非常活泼
very sprightly.
女士是位有文笔的写信人
The lady was a charming correspondent.
但是我向你保证Dovercourt伯爵
But I assure you the Earl of Dovercourt
不会欣赏它们
will fail to appreciate them.
不过 如果你不这么想
However, if you think otherwise,
这不过是桩生意
it's purely a matter of business.
如果你认为这对你的委托人是最好的
If you think it in the best interests of your client
那掏出那么一大笔钱的确太蠢了
then it would indeed be foolish to pay so large a sum of money.
你说得太快了
You go too fast.
在这么一件棘手的事上 我们当然是要尽力避免丑闻
We would certainly make every effort to avoid scandal in so delicate a matter.
我肯定你也是这么想的
I felt sure that you see it in that light.
你这该死的
Damn you.
Eva小姐不是个富有的人
Lady Eva is not a wealthy woman.
2000英镑
Two thousand pounds
是她所有的积蓄
would be total drain on her resources.
你说的那个数字她完全负担不起
The sum you named utterly beyond her power.
让我们以这个价钱赎回信吧
Return the letters at the price we indicate,
我向你保证
I assure you,
这是你能拿到的最高价
it is the highest you can get.
你说那是小姐的所有积蓄也许是真的
What you say maybe true of the lady's resources
但是一旦结婚
but the surely the occasion of her marriage
不正是她的朋友和亲人
is it not a proper time for her friends and relations
助她一臂之力的时候吗?
to make some little effort on her behalf?
他们可能正犹豫送什么结婚礼物
They may hesitate as to an acceptable wedding present
但是这一扎信
but this little bundle of letters
带了的余兴
would bring more joy
将远多于伦敦所有的宴会
than all the candelabras and butter dishes in London
不是吗?
wouldn't it?
这不可能
It is not possible.
啊 天哪
Oh dear me then.
真是不幸啊
How very unfortunate.
我觉得小姐们都被糟糕地建议 不要去做什么尝试
I cannot help feeling that ladies are ill advised in not making an effort.
看看这个
Look at this.
这个属于...
This belongs to,
也许不该告诉你们这是属于谁的
well perhaps it's hardly fair to tell you to whom it belongs
直到明天早上它们到女士的丈夫手中
until tomorrow morning when it will be in the hands of the lady's husband.
只是因为她筹不到这么一点小钱
And all because she will not find a beggarly sum
原本是很容易办到的事
which she could easily do
只要把她的一些钻石换成人工珠宝的就行
simply by turning some of her diamonds into paste.
多么可惜啊!
It is such a pity!
你或许在最近的晨报上
You may have noticed a small paragraph
注意到一篇短讯
recently in the Morning Post.
尊贵的Miles小姐和Dorking上校
The sudden end of the engagement
突然终止了彼此的婚约
between the Honorable Miss Miles and Colonel Dorking?
是啊 真是个不幸的结局
Yes and it's tragic consequences.
你也可以把它称为谋杀
You can almost call it murder.
你怎么回应此事呢 Milverton先生?
How do you answer for that Mr. Milverton?
在那种情形下
How a man conducts himself
一个人做出怎样的行为
under such circumstances
都是他自己的决定
is a matter for himself alone.
那是不义之财!
That is a monstrous accession.
是你
It was you
你一个人害死了他
and you alone who caused his death.
就为了那点钱
And the sum involved niggardly.
确实才1200磅
Indeed a mere twelve hundred pounds
就可以解决所有的问题
would have settled the whole questions.
很可惜 不是吗?
Pitiful isn't it?
但是我发现福尔摩斯先生
And yet I find you Mr. Holmes,
作为一个明白人
a man of sense,
居然拿你们委托人全部未来和荣耀 和我谈条件
boggling over terms when the whole future and honor of your client is at stake.
你让我很吃惊 真的很吃惊
You surprise me. You do really.
找不到那么多钱
The money cannot be found.
最好你接受我们提出的价钱
Surely it would be better for you to take the substantial sum we offer
而不是毁了她的前程
than to ruin this young woman's career,
不然什么也得不到
which can profit you in no way.
那你就错了
But you're mistaken.
曝光此事会间接使我
An exposure would profit me indirectly
受到很大的益处
to a considerable degree.
我还有八件 十件
I have eight or ten
类似的事情要去谈
similar cases materializing.
要是Eva小姐的不幸能成为事例流传开
If it is circulated that I have made a severe example of Lady Eva.
会使其余的人
I'll shall find the rest
更理智一些
much more open to reason.
你们明白我的意思了?
Do you see my point?
我们来看看这些信的内容
Let us see the contents of those letters.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯 我以为你会做些有创意的事情
Mr. Holmes I've been expecting you to do something original.
这早就司空见惯了
This has been tried so often before.
小Edward Kroft就是其中一个
Young Edward Kroft for one.
Kroft?
那个男仆Veitch
The footman Veitch
替你挡下了本该射向你的子弹
who took the bullet that was rightfully yours.
你调查过我
You've done some work on me.
那你一定知道
So you must know
没有什么能靠近伤害我
that nothing ever came of an attack on my person.
我武装到了牙齿
I'm armed to the teeth
一直是这样
at all times
无时无刻不准备着使用武器
and I'm perfectly prepared to use my weapons
我知道法律会保护我
and knowing that the law will support me.
你或许有机会来检验一下这套理论
You may well have your chance to test your assumption.
Hudson太太 别让人来打扰我
Mrs. Hudson I am not to be disturbed.
走吧
Go.
福尔摩斯 你不会真认为
Mr. Holmes surely you don't believe
我会傻到把谋生的东西随身携带吧?
I'd be so foolish to carry my livelihood here in my pocket?
只是为了确认一下 Milverton先生
Just making sure Mr. Milverton.
那么 现在 先生们
Well now gentlemen,
我今晚还有一两个小约会
I have one or two little interviews this evening
从这到Hampstead还很远
and it's a long drive to Hampstead.
有人给了Milverton一点教训
Now someone has dealt Milverton a blow.
一个愤怒的丈夫
An outraged husband
和其余在这个灰暗的城市里数以千计人一样
just as there are thousands in this grey city
盼着Milverton去死
who crave Milverton's destruction
或许会先我们一步
and may yet beat us to it.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
我和任何人一样爱好艺术
I'm as fond of art as any man
但是你不认为在昨天的谈话之后...
but don't you think after yesterday's encounter...
艺术离不开头脑
Art is bond to the brain
特别是在做决定的时候
especially in moments of decision.
我们了解了一些Milverton的情况
So we've learned something about Milverton.
他的残忍无情很难被曝光
That he's ruthless is hardly a revelation.
他的虚荣
And that of his vanity
就是他的弱点
and to a certain his vulnerability.
被砍坏的马车
I can see that the damage to his carriage
也许让他有些不安
might have unsettled him.
我们一定要利用这些事
We must exploit such things.
肆无忌惮的蓄意破坏
Wanton vandalism.
"盔甲上出现了裂缝" (他的防备有了漏洞)
Any chink in the armor.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes
这是我的朋友
this is my friend
尊敬的Charlotte Miles
the Honorable Charlotte Miles.
这为是夏洛克福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes
和他的搭档华生先生
and his partner Mr. Watson.
Eva小姐能和您单独谈谈吗?
Lady Eva may speak privately to you?
Miles太太
Mrs. Miles
请接受我们的慰问
please accept our sympathy.
福尔摩斯先生和我
Mr. Holmes and I
都知道您的情况
are fully aware of your situation.
很感谢你 华生医生
That is most kind of you Doctor Watson
但人要带着自己的错误活下去
but one has to live with one's mistakes.
他不肯让步
He was unyielding.
现在 下一步
Now the next move
需要你完全的配合
requires your delicate cooperation.
我会按你说的做
I'll do anything you say Mr. Holmes.
舞会在哪天?
The dance in your honor?
14号
On the 14th.
下午好 Stokes先生?
Good afternoon Mr. Stokes?
我说过别让人打扰我 姑娘
I told you I was not to be disturbed girl
什么事?
what is it?
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生想见你
It's Mr. Sherlock Holmes to see you sir.
"Aggie 我被你打动了"
"Oh Aggie, you've touched my heart."
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
我是来通知你
I'm here to inform you
我的委托人已经接受了你的条件
that my client accepts your terms.
她的做法是明智的
She's acted with perspicacity.
她有个小小的请求
She begs but a small favor.
是什么?
What is it?
她想把交易延迟到15号进行
That the exchange be delayed until the 1 5th.
在它前一天晚上 伯爵安排了一个舞会
The Earl has arranged a dance for the previous night
她需要专注于那事
and she is somewhat preoccupied with that.
舞会 是的
The dance yes.
那第二天的10点
So 1 0 o'clock the following morning
我们交易 行吗?
we can do business?
7000英镑?
Seven thousand pounds?
对
As agreed.
在这还是在贝克街?
Here or at Baker's Street?
这里或贝克街
Here, Baker Street.
也许找一个中立的地方
Neutral ground perhaps.
Diogenes俱乐部
The Diogenes club
你是它的会员吧?
you are a member?
可以吗?
May I?
告诉我这种突然的转变
Tell me this sudden turnabout
是你的建议吗?
was it on your advice?
我不能让我的委托人听天由命
I could not abandon my client to her fate
Milverton先生 你胜利了
Mr. Milverton. You are the victor.
真是天赐的芳香
What a divine fragrance.
我去世的丈夫和我 就是她第二个家
My late husband and I were something of a second family to her
所以你明白我的忧虑了?
so you see my concern?
那个勒索她的人?
This man who is blackmailing her?
Charles Augustus Milverton
他是个画商
he's an arts dealer.
是的
Yes.
我听说过他
I've heard of him.
他收集流言
He's well placed to hear the gossip
然后作恶
and do his worst.
福尔摩斯先生怎么想?
What view does Mr. Holmes take of it?
他自有主张
Well I'm sure he has something in mind
但是他经常是最后才让我知道
but he seldom confides in me till the last minute.
福尔摩斯
Awe Holmes.
Swinstead女士很关心这件事
Lady Swinstead is fully primed for the situation.
时间快没有了
Time is running out
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
要是钱有问题...
If it is a question of paying the money...
那没必要
That will not be necessary.
那你能保证了?
You can give assurance then?
这么说可能有点轻率 Swinstead夫人
That would be unwise in me Lady Swinstead
但是我向您保证
but I assure you
我会尽我所能
I will give it my best.
那样我会很满意
I shall have to be satisfied with that then.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
这个人一定要闭嘴
This man must be silenced.
她知道Milverton吗?
Does she know about Milverton?
他的名字?
A name?
是的  我告诉她了
Yes I told her.
我错了吗?
Was that wrong of me?
华生 这些钱
Oh Watson these bills,
必须要付
they must be paid.
顺便说一句 我确保了我们
Oh, incidentally I managed to secure
都被邀请去参见Dovercourt的舞会
an invitation for us both to the Dovercourt dance.
虽然离伦敦有点远
The house is some miles from London
但是离我的目标近了
but in reach for my purposes.
什么目标?
What purposes?
我要在那天晚上 潜入Milverton家偷窃
I intend to burgle the Milverton house that night.
天啊 福尔摩斯
For heaven sakes Holmes
想想你在干什么!
think what you're doing.
让我们好好地想清楚
Well let us look at it fairly and clearly.
你得承认
You will admit
这件事从道义上来说是正义的
that the cause is morally justifiable.
是的
Yes.
在法律上是犯罪
Technically criminal.
不过是像抢他的钱包
No more than raiding his pockets ,
你那时就愿意帮我
a cause which you were perfectly willing to help me.
那时事出突然
That was on the spurt of the moment
不是理智的
not on the coal light of reason.
理智?
Reason?
这件事里有"理智"的用武之地吗 华生?
Is there reasoning to be done Watson?
没有一样要我动脑子
Nothing to test my brain?
可恶
That's the curse of it.
想想
Think.
要是你被抓了
If you're caught,
这份令人尊敬的事业
an honored career
就会彻底完蛋 在公众前颜面丢尽
ending in failure and public disgrace.
什么完蛋 什么丢脸
What failure? What disgrace?
能比得上被打败?
Against defeat.
你再了解我不过
You know me well enough
如果有别的可能
that I would never adopt so objectionable a course
我是不会出此下策
if another were possible.
我必须拿到那些信
I must have those letters.
我对那房子了如指掌
And have the house in the palm of my hand.
先动手再动脑
The cudgel before the brain.
那讨厌的Milverton呢?
What of the odious Milverton?
难道他会敞开大门请你大摇大摆进去吗?
Do you think he's just going to open his gates and invite you to stroll in?
Milverton会去舞会
Milverton will be at the dance
作为Eva小姐的客人
as the guest of Lady Eva's.
太荒谬了 福尔摩斯
That's monstrous Holmes.
我赌上了自尊和名誉
My self-respect and reputation are at stake
这是唯一的办法
it's the only way.
我不喜欢这样
Well I don't like it,
一点也不
any of it.
没什么可怕的
You have nothing to fear.
Eva?
Hudson太太  谁让你给我整理的?
Mrs. Hudson why did you tidy for me?
我的鞋呢?
Where the hell are my shoes?
鞋?
Shoes?
是的
Yes.
面具?
Masks?
黑丝手绢
Black silk handkerchief.
我看你天生就会这些事
I see you have a natural turn for this sort of thing.
我也很纳闷自己怎么学来的
I wonder where I learned it.
今晚要像平时一样小心提防
Take the usual precautions tonight.
Hebworth
Hebworth.
我会的
I will.
祝您愉快
Enjoy your evening.
这的人都有危险 福尔摩斯 (会成为下个受害者)
The people are at risks here Holmes.
确实是这样
Yes indeed.
我们8分钟后走
We leave in eight minutes.
打扰一下 先生
Excuse me sir,
夫人在楼上想见你
Her ladyship would like to see you upstairs.
Harry
Harry.
那个人
That man
他是被邀请的客人吗?
is he an invited guest?
Milverton
Milverton.
是的 是Eva的想法
Yes it's something Eva schemed.
那副画
The painting.
聪明的姑娘很可能 是想压低价钱才邀请他来
The old girl is probably trying to whittle down the price by inviting him here.
别担心 Diana
Don't worry yourself Diana.
没事
It's all right.
太奇怪了
How strange
在这看见你 福尔摩斯先生
to see you here Mr. Holmes.
生意娱乐两不误?
Mixing business with pleasure?
毫无疑问你也是
There's no doubt you are.
我今晚是纯粹来玩的 福尔摩斯 我向你保证
purely pleasure this evening Mr. Holmes I assure you
你会遵守我们的约定吧
You will be keeping our appointment.
先生
Sir.
我的访客半小时到
I am expecting a visitor in an half an hour.
是 先生
Sir.
主人走了 仆人就开始享乐
Servants are playing while the master's away.
福尔摩斯
Holmes?
Milvertons的马车
Milvertons carriage
没时间关门了
no time to lose the door.
你使我缩短了今晚的娱乐时间
You made me curtail my evening's entertainment.
我希望你证明那是值得的
I hope you prove worth it.
你不能挑个更适合交谈的时间来吗?
You couldn't have come at a more sociable time?
好吧 不行就算了吧
Well if you couldn't, you couldn't
要是伯爵夫人是个严厉的女主人
if the Countess is a hard mistress
你现在有机会报复她了
you have a chance now to get even with her.
上帝保佑  你怎么在发抖?
Bless the girl, what are you shivering about?
对!
That's right!
打起精神
Pull yourself together.
我们来谈生意
Now then, let's get down to business.
你说你有5封
You save you have five letters,
关于D' Albert伯爵夫人的信?
which compromise the Countess D' Albert?
你要卖 我要买
You want to sell them. I want to buy them.
目前为止一切顺利
So far, so good.
就剩下谈好价钱了
So it remains to fix the price.
当然我要先检查这些信
Of course I shall want to examine the letters.
如果内容够好...
If they prove to be good specimens then...
天啊 是你?
Great heavens, it is you?
一个被你毁了一生的女人
A woman who's life you have ruined.
你太固执了
You were so obstinate.
-12年前 法国 -为什么你要把我逼上绝路呢?
-Paris twelve years ago. -Why did you drive me to such extremities?
一段被尘封的往事
An episode long closed.
我本连一个苍蝇都不愿伤害
I wouldn't hurt a fly of my own accord.
你一直等待
You waited for the moment
直到能赢得最大的赌注的时候
when the stakes was most worth winning.
我能怎么做?
What was I to do?
-我出的价钱你完全能负担 -你把信给我丈夫
-I put the price well within your means. -Instead you sent the letters to my husband.
-因为你没有付钱! -一个我连为他系鞋都配不上的人
-You would not pay. -A man whose boots I was never worthy to lace-
你伤了他高贵的心
you broke his gallant heart,
你这混蛋
vial creature.
那天我来求你
That day I came here I prayed,
发发善心
I begged you for mercy,
你却当面嘲弄我
and you laughed in my face
就像你现在这样
as you are trying to laugh now,
你懦弱的内心 使你的嘴唇不住地颤动
your coward heart cannot keep you lips from twitching.
别以为你能吓到我
Don't imagine that you can bully me
-我只要提高声音 -你不会再伤害别人了
-I'm only to raise my voice -You will ruin no more lives.
-我可以叫来我的仆人 逮捕你 -你再也不能像折磨我这样
-I can call my servantsand have you arrested. -You will wring no more hearts
-折磨别人了 Charles Milverton -我可以容忍你对我发火
-as you have wrung mine Charles Milverton. -I will make allowance for your natural anger.
只要你马上离开
Leave the room at once
我就什么也不说了
and I'll say no more about it.
我要替天行道
I will free the world of a poisonous thing.
你杀了我
You've done me.
放火里去
The fire.
Swinstead夫人
Lady Swinstead
你自由了
you're free.
快跑!
Run!
现在 先生们
Now gentlemen
要拍卖的是
the sale of the property
已故Charles A. Milverton的物品
of Charles A. Milverton described, deceased.
第一个
Lot one,
一盒子杂物
a box of miscellaneous objects,
小饰品
trinkets,
信件
correspondence,
5磅?
do hear five pounds?
谢谢 先生
Thank you sir.
Vetron家政的Stuart
The stuart from the Vetron household
我肯定
making sure.
第二件
Lot two,
雅典娜的半身像
bust of Athena,
古代智慧 工业 和战争的女神
ancient Goddess of wisdom, industry and war.
有人愿意为这尊大理石像出价吗?
Now what do I have for this fine marble statue?
10磅?
Ten pounds?
有人出20磅?
Twenty?
20磅
Twenty pounds.
有人出30磅吗?
Thirty?
30磅
I have thirty pounds.
50磅
Fifty.
50磅了 先生
I have fifty pounds sir.
有人出60磅
Sixty?
有人出80磅
Eighty?
80磅
Eighty pounds.
有人出90磅
Ninety?
这位先生出了90磅
Ninety pounds against you sir.
90磅
At ninety.
100磅
One hundred pounds.
还有更高的吗?
More sir?
卖给那边的先生了
Sold to the gentleman over there
以100磅的价钱
for one hundred pounds.
福尔摩斯先生!
Mr. Holmes.
从拍卖会上买的 Hudson太太
Bought it in an auction Mrs. Hudson.
花了100磅
It cost a hundred pounds.
他为什么要砸碎它呢?
Why has he smashed it?
我以为里面有什么
I thought there might be something in it.
很高兴我错了
I'm more than happy to say that I was wrong.
谢谢 Hudson太太
Thank you Mrs. Hudson
福尔摩斯 那个法国人为什么还要它?
why is a point of interest Holmes did the Frenchman want it?
感情用事吧
Sentimental reasons.
只是想确认一下
Just making sure.
别写了 华生
No Watson.
有些地方我都觉得不光彩
There are certain aspects in which I am not proud.
请你
Please
把这个故事
bury this case
藏在你的兜里吧
deep in your pocket.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com